Guide to the Stephen Sandy Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- June 2009 Acquisition, 1925-2009; 12; 5.33; (7 boxes) + 1 broadside folder
  - Bennington College Material
    - Coleman, Liz (President of Bennington College, 1987-2009) (Box 39)
      "File No. Two": correspondence, including letters to and from students concerning the Booth House Party and vandalism (resignation of Jonathan Sherman from Judicial Committee); college documents concerning restructuring; clippings concerning new firings; material concerning Sexual Harassment "classes"; spat in Bennington Banner between Jamaica Kincaid and Mary Oliver; Trustees play, lyrics (parodying & using Gilbert & Sullivan) on the occasion of retirement from board by Barr
    - Bennington College Trustees, 1994-1997 (Box 39)
      Correspondence, "galleys" (freely distributed opinion sheets) to and from Trustees, concerning 1994 Firings; "Steering Committee"
    - Dewey house party photographs, 1993 (Box 39)
      Rock The House. Bennington: Dewey House, Bennington College, 1993. Xerox collection of photographs. Cross-dress party at Bennington. Includes "Sex & Drugs" survey. Letter from Tom Gross. Elder man dancing is Chi-chung Huang, "C.C." Final page shows graffiti: "Liz Why Are You Killing Our School?"
  - Photographs and Other Papers
    - Photograph album, undated (Box 39)
      Camping and climbing trip to Washington, Mts. Baker & Shuksan, with David Lein
    - Photograph album, 1949 (Box 39)
      Valley and A2Z Guest Ranch, Wyoming
    - Photograph album, 1967 (Box 39)
      SS first real estate, house and acres at 'Bear Mountain' (Wendell, Mass) 1967
    - The Marriage Service Revised, 1925 (Box 39)
      Souvenir of marriage of Stephen Sandy's parents, Alan and Evelyn, signed by them.
    - Guy, Georges. Translations of two poems by Stephen Sandy, 1971-1980s (Box 39)
      In two wrappers Japanese woodcut-printed washi paper. 1) "Intersection" (from Roofs). 2) "Ikebana," "Danse et Triomphe du Prince Genji," "Bouddhas Anciens," "Jardin de Mousse (Carte Postale)," "Faubourg," "Conférence," "La Tombe De Claudel." (All these texts are from Roofs, Houghton Mifflin, 1971).
    - Group photographs, 1978, 2006 (Box 39)
      Stephen Sandy with Robert Bly; with Liam Rector on left, Frank Bidart on right; with Arturo Vivante in Wellfleet; with Robt Bly; with Robert Creeley; with Phebe Chao at Bennington College; with Steve Kuzma, (photo John Movius); with (left to right) Jill Hoffman, Mike Malinowitz, Evelyn Horowitz [obscured by] John Ashbery, Bennington, 1978; with Andrew Hudgins (MacDowell); with William Kennedy at American Academy, 2006.
    - "Abstract" color photo image by "Joel" (friend and care provider for Tobias Schneebaum)., circa 2000 (Box 39)
    - Stephen Sandy as a boy, circa 14, in Buick convertible., circa 1948 (Box 39)
    - Kenneth Noland Handmade Papers, 1978 (Box 39)
      Tyler Graphics: Bedford Village, NY: 1978. Essay by Judith Goldman. Contains "Horizontal Stripes II", original of Noland's image for cover for Riding to Greylock.
    - Awards and recognitions, 1955-2006 (Box 39)
    - Military, 1951-1999 (Box 39)
    - Harvard University diploma. Master of Arts, 1958 (Box 40)
    - Yale University. Diploma. B.A., 1955 (Box 40)
    - Dunster House, Harvard College, by Dunster House Senior Common Room, 1962 (Box 40)
    - United States Army, Commission. Stephen Sandy Reserve Officer grade Second Lieutenant, US Army, 1957 June 27 (Box 40)
    - Scrapbook of Japan, 1967-1968 (Box 41)
      Tokyo. Maps of how to get to an address, find low places; as Barthes, L'Empire des Signes, (influence on Stephen Sandy at the time)
  - Posters and Broadsides
    - [Poster for Reading], Steven Henry Madoff presents. 57th Street Poetry Series. October 12: Stephen Sandy, Katha Pollitt. November 9: Grace Schulman, Fred. Morgan; January 11: Louis Simpson, Sharon Olds; Feb 15, Amy Clampitt, Dana Gioia. Oscarsson-Hood Gallery. Sponsored by the Center for Book Arts. [c. 1985]., circa 1985 (Box 42 (Broadside))
    - O'Grady, Desmond. Irish poet resident in Cambridge & Harvard (later living in Italy), c. 1970. Calligraphic doodle on two sides sheet, (mis)quoting Pound. Signed D. O'Grady, 70. Boston., circa 1970 (Box 42 (Broadside))
    - "John Hay Poetry Series Presents Stephen Sandy," Sponsored by the Brown University Libraries, 1970 December 3 (Box 42 (Broadside))
    - Riot of Peace. Stephen Sandy Poetry Reading. Memorial Hall, [1969] October 25 (Box 42 (Broadside))
      Location: possibly Mt. Holyoke or Williams College
    - Harry Mathews At Bennington College. Signed by Mathews. Design by Stephen Sandy., [1990] May 26 (Box 42 (Broadside))
    - Sandy, Stephen. 2 Images, handmade paper, work with Kenneth Noland, 1980. '"Greenland' Sandy, '80." "Sunspots," 1980. (Box 42 (Broadside))
- June 2011 Acquisition, 1961-2011; 13; 2.09; (5 boxes)
  Organized under three headings: Musical Scores, Writings, and Correspondence
  Box 45 (audio recordings): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  The June 2011 Acquisition consists of printed musical scores featuring text by Stephen Sandy, writings, and correspondence. Writings consist chiefly of drafts and fair copies of individual poems, accompanied by notes that document each poem's publication history. Also included are proofs of book-length publications accompanied by correspondence with editors. Correspondence consists of a single autograph letter, signed, from Arturo Vivante to Stephen Sandy.
  - Musical Scores
    - The Aids Quilt Songbook, 1992-1993 (Box 43)
    - "A Dissolve", 1970 (Box 43)
    - "Light in Spring Poplars", 1970-1987; 2 (Box 43)
    - "The Breakers Pound", 1983-1989 (Box 43)
    - "Sang the Turkey", undated (Box 43)
    - "The Second Law", 1991, 1999 (Box 43)
    - "This Chill Air", 1999 (Box 43)
    - "What Are You Held Out For?", 1989 (Box 43)
    - "Vita de Sancto Hieronymo", 1973 (Box 44)
    - "A Vermont Quartet", 1984 (Box 44)
    - "Moving Out", 1976 (Box 44)
    - "Stresses in the Peacable Kingdom. The Choral Music of Richard Wilson", 1999; (1 compact disk) (Box 45)
      (audio and video recordings): ‡a Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - "Drifts and Shadows: American Song for the New Millennium", 2008; (1 compact disk) (Box 45)
      Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Writings
    - "Amarna Relief", 2007-2008 (Box 46)
    - "Anniversary", undated (Box 46)
    - "Art is Largely a Question of Slowing Down", undated (Box 46)
    - "As Smoke Robes Fire", undated (Box 46)
    - "Attic Tenants", undated (Box 46)
    - "Aubade", undated (Box 46)
    - "Austin Tower", undated (Box 46)
    - "The Awkward Age", undated (Box 46)
    - "Banal Testament" (empty folder), undated (Box 46)
    - "Bannerman's Windows", circa 1985 (Box 46)
    - "The Baro", undated (Box 46)
    - "Ben's Tathagata", undated (Box 46)
    - "Blue Map", [1996] June 26 (Box 46)
    - "Breaking Up", undated (Box 46)
    - "C's Island", circa 1990 (Box 46)
    - "Canada", undated (Box 46)
    - "Charley", 1967-1971 (Box 46)
    - "Chautauqua", 1977 (Box 46)
    - "Circular Drives", undated (Box 46)
    - "A Common", undated (Box 46)
    - "Cormoran's Island", 1960s (Box 46)
    - "Corpus", undated (Box 46)
    - "The Crandall Goose", circa 2008 (Box 46)
    - "The Day Van Gogh Vanished", undated (Box 46)
    - "Dealing, 1928", undated (Box 46)
    - "Detention Period", 1995 (Box 46)
    - "Dinner for Two", undated (Box 46)
    - "Down on the Levee", undated (Box 46)
    - "Emptying Air", undated (Box 46)
    - "Epistle to Andrew", undated (Box 46)
    - "Figure on a Wooded Path", 1984 July (Box 46)
    - "Fourth Dimension", undated (Box 46)
    - "Like Frisbies Through Air", undated (Box 46)
    - "O From Our Banal Infancy", 1986 (Box 46)
    - "Glasses & a Blank Check", 1972 (Box 46)
    - "Grounds", 1996 April 28 (Box 46)
    - "Guerilla Love This Year", 1967 (Box 46)
    - "Halloween Away", undated; 2 (Box 46)
    - "Historic Preservation", undated (Box 46)
    - "If Not You, Who", undated (Box 46)
    - "In a Dream So Much", undated (Box 46)
    - "Iron Verity", undated (Box 46)
    - "Japan Suite", undated (Box 46)
    - "Jumble", 2006, undated (Box 46)
    - "Kimpel the Thinker", undated (Box 46)
    - "Ladybug", 2010, undated (Box 46)
    - "Late Cretaceous Reverie", undated (Box 46)
    - "Leaving Calcutta", 1968 (Box 46)
    - "A Life Without Speed Bumps", undated (Box 46)
    - "A Maiden Voyage", 1991 (Box 46)
    - "Mid August Vermont With Sky", undated (Box 46)
    - "Milligan", undated (Box 46)
    - "Miracle Milk Moustache", circa 2007 (Box 46)
    - "Message to a Wound", undated (Box 46)
    - "Mushroom Poem", undated (Box 46)
    - "My Fount", undated (Box 46)
    - "Nailed", undated (Box 46)
    - "The Near Shelf", undated (Box 46)
    - "Needing, this Fugue", undated (Box 46)
    - "Night Blooming Cereus", undated (Box 46)
    - "Night in Shibuya", undated (Box 46)
    - "North by Northwest", undated (Box 46)
    - "Old News", 1990-2011 (Box 46)
    - "On First Looking for Hale-Bopp", undated (Box 46)
    - "Party Line", undated (Box 46)
    - "Penetralium", undated (Box 46)
    - "Petering", undated (Box 46)
    - "Picasso, Drawing", undated (Box 46)
    - "The Players", undated (Box 46)
    - "Polylocal", undated (Box 46)
    - "Possum", undated (Box 46)
    - "Reading about Language in a Garden", circa 1981 (Box 46)
    - "Recitative for Chicago, August 1968", undated (Box 46)
    - "Reliquary", undated (Box 46)
    - "A Report of Glorias", undated (Box 46)
    - "Roaring Spring", undated (Box 46)
    - "Sadness Like Death ... as the Circles Wheel", undated (Box 46)
    - "Sap Moon Journal", undated (Box 46)
    - "September 5", undated (Box 46)
    - "Shutters", undated (Box 46)
    - "Side Hill Farm", undated (Box 46)
    - "Sixes and Sevens", undated (Box 46)
    - "Silence, Exile", undated (Box 46)
    - "Skaters", 1979 July 3 (Box 46)
    - "Small Wonder", undated (Box 46)
    - "Spell", undated (Box 46)
    - "Spring Again", 1981 (Box 46)
    - "If, on Sweltering Nights in Cambridge", undated (Box 46)
    - "Tacit Blue", undated (Box 46)
    - "Take Back Vermont", undated (Box 46)
    - "These Vineyards, these Farms", undated (Box 46)
    - "Toshiya's Cats", undated (Box 46)
    - "Tropic Handbook", undated (Box 46)
    - "Turnkey Blues", undated (Box 46)
    - "Two for Tu Mu", undated (Box 46)
    - "Odysseus", undated (Box 46)
    - "Veil", undated (Box 46)
    - "Vertigo, Ashbery's French Philosophy Under My Seat", undated (Box 46)
    - "Voices & Visions", circa 1990 (Box 46)
    - "Walking, Sitting, Climbing", 1980s (Box 46)
    - "Western Fiction", undated (Box 46)
    - "What Do I Know? It's Nothing Really", undated (Box 46)
    - "What Can You Say", 1996 June 29 (Box 46)
    - "Where Are You Going with that Wrench?", undated (Box 46)
    - "The White Bull of Marrault", 1961, undated; 2 (Box 46)
    - "Windswept", undated (Box 46)
    - "Wingaersheek Beach", undated (Box 46)
    - "The World", undated (Box 46)
    - The French Circuit, 2008 (Box 46)
    - Grunts, undated (Box 47)
    - Netsuke Days, 2008, undated; 4 (Box 47)
    - Overlook, 2009-2010; 2 (Box 47)
    - Paying Guest, untitled (Box 47)
    - Pray Remember the Grotto, 2006 February 14 (Box 47)
    - Shapes of Time, undated (Box 47)
    - Weathers Permitting, 2004 December 15 (Box 47)
    - Waxwings, undated (Box 47)
    - Satori, undated (Box 47)
  - Correspondence
    - Autograph letter, signed, from Arturo Vivante to Stephen Sandy, 2004 March 28 (Box 47)
- December 2011 Acquisition, 1967-2011; 14; 1.21; (2 boxes)
  Box 48 (computer disk): Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  The June 2009 Acquisition consists of correspondence and subject files. Correspondence consists chiefly of professional and personal letters from writers and literary organizations, documenting the literary community in which Sandy is active. Other subject files consist of material relating to a particular person or topic (e.g. St. Johnsbury Athenaeum Reading).
  - Correspondence and Subject Files
    - Ashbery, John, 2010 (Box 48)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 2006, undated (Box 48)
    - Antonakos, Stephen, 2010-2011 (Box 48)
    - The Atlantic Monthly, 1988-2009 (Box 48)
    - Bagg, Robert, 2008, undated (Box 48)
    - Barnet, Peter, 2007-2011; 1 folder, 1 computer disk (Box 48)
      Existence and Location of Originals
      Also stored in: Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information. Disk # 2011.ycal.29.0001, Fibula, November 2008.
    - Barr, John, 2010 (Box 48)
    - Bly, Robert, 2004-2009 (Box 48)
    - Breaking Story, 2010 (Box 48)
    - Brookhouse, Christopher, 2009-2011 (Box 48)
    - Corbett, William, 2010 (Box 48)
    - DeNiord, Chard, 2005-2011 (Box 48)
    - Du Passage, Mary, 2009-2010 (Box 48)
    - Easterly, John, 2009-2011 (Box 48)
    - Ebbinghaus, Susanne, 2008-2009 (Box 48)
    - Eley, Elem, 2008-2009 (Box 48)
    - Eley, Eide O., 2008-2009 (Box 48)
    - Farhang, Mansour, 2010 January (Box 48)
    - Gowrie, Grey, 2008-2011 (Box 48)
    - Gregg, Jonathan, 1997 (Box 48)
    - Hadas, Rachel, 2008-2011 (Box 48)
    - Hall, Donald, 2009-2011 (Box 48)
    - Hays, Mary, 2011 (Box 48)
    - Hoagland, Edward and Trudy Carter, 2005-2011 (Box 48)
    - Hollander, John, 2002-2005 (Box 48)
    - Houghton Mifflin, 1967-1974 (Box 48)
    - Hubbard, Sue, 1999, 2009 (Box 48)
    - Hull, Karen (outgoing), 1986 August 18 (Box 48)
    - Irby, Ken (Box 48)
    - Kayafas, Peter, 2002 (Box 48)
    - Kernan, Margot Starr, 2007-2010 (Box 48)
    - Kinnell, Galway, 2011 (Box 48)
    - Kunitz, Stanley, 1992-2005 (Box 48)
    - Louisiana State University Press (empty folder) (Box 48)
    - MacLeish, Archibald, [no year] October 14 (Box 48)
    - Magowan, Robin, 2009, undated (Box 48)
    - Maguire, Greg, 2009-2010 (Box 48)
    - Massimilla, Stephen, 2011 (Box 48)
    - Mathews, Harry, 2010-2011 (Box 48)
    - Mogelson, Luke, 2011 (Box 48)
    - Morgan, Ted, 2010-2011 (Box 48)
    - Muldoon, Paul, 2008-2010 (Box 48)
    - Lathbury, Roger, 1995-2004 (Box 48)
    - Peters, Robert, 1974 February 23 (Box 48)
    - Philips, Carl, 2009-2010 (Box 48)
    - Pollan, Michael, 2011 (Box 48)
    - Randall, Lilian, 2009-2011 (Box 48)
    - Reeve, F. D., 2008-2011 (Box 48)
    - Ruefle, Mary, 2008-2011 (Box 48)
    - Ruffin, Paul, 1986 September 11 (Box 48)
    - Shawn, Allen, 2007-2011 (Box 48)
    - Shipley, Julia, 2010 (Box 48)
    - Souter, David, 2009 July 15 (Box 48)
    - Spivack, Kathleen, 2011 (Box 48)
    - St. Armand, Barton L., 2008-2011 (Box 48)
    - St. Johnsbury Athenaeum Reading, 2008, undated (Box 48)
    - Svoboda, Terese, 2011 (Box 48)
    - Swenson, Karen, 2010-2011 (Box 48)
    - Takashima, Makoto, 1969 (Box 48)
    - Thorne, Oak Leigh, 2010 (Box 48)
    - Viscusi, Margo, 2011 May 11 (Box 48)
    - Waldrop, Keith & Rosmarie, 1971-1972, undated (Box 48)
    - Weathers Permitting, 2006-2008 (Box 48)
    - Western Humanities Review, 2007-2011 (Box 48)
    - Wilbur, Richard, 2008-2011 (Box 48)
    - Wilson, Richard, 2009 (Box 48)
    - Wolff, Rebecca, 2000, 2011 (Box 48)
    - Yale Art Gallery, Poet Project, 1999-2000 (Box 48)
    - Yale Reunion, 2003-2005 (Box 48)
  - Computer media
    (computer disks):Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
- February 2012 Acquisition (Restricted Fragile Material), undated; 15; 0.21; (1 box)
  (computer disks) Restricted Fragile Material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
- July 2012 Acquisition, 1945-2012; 16; 3.09; (6 boxes)
  Organized under two headings: Writings, and Other Papers.
  The July 2012 Acquisition consists of writings, ephemera, and printed material. Writings consists of drafts (autograph manuscript, typescript, and printouts) and proofs of individual poems and other writings. Other papers include additional writings of Stephen Sandy (chiefly juvenilia), printed material, and ephemera.
  - Writings
    Chiefly arranged alphabetically. Unsorted material is filed at the end of the list.
    - "A Barn", 1980s (Box 51)
    - "A Frame", late 1960s (Box 51)
    - "Abandoned Houses", 1988 (Box 51)
    - "Abdication", 1960s (Box 51)
    - "Admas in Japan", 2000 (Box 51)
    - "Aftermath", 2007 (Box 51)
    - "Air for Air", circa 1975 (Box 51)
    - "Akhnaten", undated (Box 51)
    - "Alchemy", 2011 (Box 51)
    - "Aleutian Solution", 2008 (Box 51)
    - "Allegheny Front", undated (Box 51)
    - "And the Other Westerners", 1970s (Box 51)
    - "An Elder at Night", undated (Box 51)
    - "An Out", 1990s (Box 51)
    - "Ancient Orchard", undated (Box 51)
    - "Arranging a Meeting", circa 1965 (Box 51)
    - "As Smoke Robes Fire", undated (Box 51)
    - "Ash Street", circa 1990 (Box 51)
    - "At Ten O'Clock", 1980s (Box 51)
    - "Austin Tower", 1966-1967 (Box 51)
    - "Bad Eau Bid O Butterfly Aubade", 1970s (Box 51)
    - "Ballet Chautauqua", 1990s (Box 51)
    - "Banal Testament", 1969 (Box 51)
    - "The Baro", 1990s (Box 51)
    - "Beads", circa 1980 (Box 51)
    - "Blitz to Boston", 1960s (Box 51)
    - "Blue Novella", 1970s (Box 51)
    - "Bluestone", 1980s (Box 51)
    - "Boss Man", undated (Box 51)
    - "Bowser", undated (Box 51)
    - "Brattle Street", undated (Box 51)
    - "Bread", undated (Box 51)
    - "Breaking Story", 2010 (Box 51)
    - "Breaking Up", 2000 (Box 51)
    - "Bridge to Hawaii", undated (Box 51)
    - "Brimfield & Blake", 2005-2010 (Box 51)
    - "Broadly Speaking", late 1990s (Box 51)
    - "Burned Bodies Hung", undated (Box 51)
    - "Bur Oaks", 2000 (Box 51)
    - "Camp Meeting", 1980s (Box 51)
    - "Canada", 1980s (Box 51)
    - "Candles", 2010 (Box 51)
    - "Carleton Coons, Retired, Thought a Racist", 1960s (Box 51)
    - "Catalogue", circa 1990 (Box 51)
    - "Cavalcante", circa 1985 (Box 51)
    - "Cellist Emptying Desk", undated (Box 51)
    - "Certificate of Domestic Partnership", 2000 (Box 51)
    - "Charles", circa 2000 (Box 51)
    - "Charley", 1960s (Box 51)
    - "Circles", circa 1985 (Box 51)
    - "Clothes and the Man", circa 1960 (Box 51)
    - "Cold Courts of Morning", 1980s (Box 51)
    - "Cold Thicket", 1990s (Box 51)
    - "Concept", 1970s (Box 51)
    - "Constables at Auction", 2008 (Box 51)
    - "Continuation in Black and White", late 1980s (Box 51)
    - "Country Auctions", 1970s (Box 51)
    - "Country of Sudden Dance", 1960s (Box 52)
    - "Cowled Autumns Hovered", 1950s (Box 52)
    - "Crandall Goose", undated (Box 52)
    - "Cunning & the Rest of It", circa 2008 (Box 52)
    - "Curtains", undated (Box 52)
    - "Dark Valleys", early 2000s (Box 52)
    - "Darkened Theater", 1994 (Box 52)
    - "Day Sleeps on the Wind", 1998 (Box 52)
    - "Days of 1937", 2000 (Box 52)
    - "Dead Marines", 1967 (Box 52)
    - "Dealing 1928", 2007-2008 (Box 52)
    - "Declaration", 1990s (Box 52)
    - "Dialog Between Flesh and Self", circa 1959 (Box 52)
    - "Diffusion Camp", 2007-2010 (Box 52)
    - "Dog Took the New Yorker", 2004-2007 (Box 52)
    - "Dominion", 1990s (Box 52)
    - "Doubler", undated (Box 52)
    - "Dozing by the Sea", 1970-1980 (Box 52)
    - "Drooling Arms", circa 2000 (Box 52)
    - "Duchess of Malfi", undated (Box 52)
    - "Dude", 2006-2008 (Box 52)
    - "East and West", 2000 (Box 52)
    - "Edda or Eddy", 1980s (Box 52)
    - "Elm Tree Farm", undated (Box 52)
    - "Emptying Air", 1995-2000 (Box 52)
    - "En Famille", circa 1985 (Box 52)
    - "Fable", 1990s (Box 52)
    - "Fall Forward", 1990s (Box 52)
    - "Familiar", circa 2008 (Box 52)
    - "Father of Shadows", 1970s (Box 52)
    - "Feature", 1980s (Box 52)
    - "Feed the World", 2007 (Box 52)
    - "Field Glasses", 2009 (Box 52)
    - "First Geraniums", circa 1980 (Box 52)
    - "Five Quartets", undated (Box 52)
    - "Flag Nights", 1960s (Box 52)
    - "Flight", 2005 (Box 52)
    - "For Ruth Stone", undated (Box 52)
    - "For the Chilly Sixties", 1960s (Box 52)
    - "Fourth Dimension", circa 2008 (Box 52)
    - "Freestone", 1970s (Box 52)
    - "Frieze", 1980s (Box 52)
    - "Fringe Benefits", 1984 (Box 52)
    - "From the First Farewell", undated (Box 52)
    - "Funeral", undated (Box 52)
    - "Funicular", 2000 (Box 52)
    - "Gerrit the Linkboy", 2008 (Box 52)
    - "Ghazal for Geldzahler", undated (Box 52)
    - "Girls Don't Like Stamps", circa 1980 (Box 52)
    - "God is Not Dead", 1960s (Box 52)
    - "Going For It", 1970s (Box 52)
    - "Grace Note", circa 1970 (Box 52)
    - "Grandmother's Windows", undated (Box 52)
    - "Grasmere", 1962 (Box 52)
    - "Great House", 2005 (Box 52)
    - "Greens at my Shoulder", 1960s (Box 52)
    - "Grenadine", 1980s (Box 52)
    - "Grounds", 1990s (Box 52)
    - "Guerilla Love This Year", 1960s (Box 53)
    - "Gun Cotton", 1967-1969 (Box 53)
    - "Hiroshima Fisherman", 1970s (Box 53)
    - "Hogback Lookout", circa 1980 (Box 53)
    - "Homecoming", circa 1970 (Box 53)
    - "Horace", undated (Box 53)
    - "How Do I Tax You?", circa 1965 (Box 53)
    - "How From Itself the Heart", undated (Box 53)
    - "Huang's Tao Te Ching", 2007 (Box 53)
    - "The Hushed World of the Novella", 1980s (Box 53)
    - "I Can't Say What You Do", 1990s (Box 53)
    - "I Lift Myself", 1970s (Box 53)
    - "I was a Butterfly", 1970s (Box 53)
    - "If Not You Who?", 2008 (Box 53)
    - "In the Hall", 2009 (Box 53)
    - "Istanbul Cross", circa 1975 (Box 53)
    - "Jerome", 1971 (Box 53)
    - "JM & his Bard", 1970s (Box 53)
    - "Jumble", undated (Box 53)
    - "Kid Death Lyric", 2000 (Box 53)
    - "Kimperl, the Thinker", 2007-2008 (Box 53)
    - "Ladybug", undated (Box 53)
    - "Landscape with Storm", 2008 (Box 53)
    - "Lateness", circa 2000 (Box 53)
    - "Leaf on the Snow", 1970s (Box 53)
    - "Like Family; Wise Foam", 1990s (Box 53)
    - "Lily", circa 1990 (Box 53)
    - "Lindow Man", 2004 (Box 53)
    - "Little Auden Ode", 1970 (Box 53)
    - "Little City by the Bay", undated (Box 53)
    - "The Living Section", undated (Box 53)
    - "Looking Off", circa 2000 (Box 53)
    - "Long Line of the Shore", 1960s (Box 53)
    - "Loss and Other Comestibles", circa 2000 (Box 53)
    - "Lost Among the Possibilities", undated (Box 53)
    - "Lotus Deciphered", 2000 (Box 53)
    - "Love of Beauty Is...", 1970s (Box 53)
    - "Love You", 1980s (Box 53)
    - "Mad Dog Rag", 1970-2010 (Box 53)
    - "Maelstrom of First Rain", 1968 (Box 53)
    - "Mailbox at the End of the Mind", 1970s (Box 53)
    - "A Maine Man Makes His Home in Iowa", 1957-1958 (Box 53)
    - "Malfunction Junction", undated (Box 53)
    - "Mall, Sweet Mall", undated (Box 53)
    - "Man Called Moses Pulled In", circa 1972 (Box 53)
    - "Marsyas", 1970s (Box 53)
    - "Mercury Retrograde", circa 2006 (Box 53)
    - "Message to a Wound", 2002-2003 (Box 53)
    - "Michelle Has Brought", undated (Box 53)
    - "Milligan", 1980s (Box 53)
    - "Modest Proposals", 1980s (Box 53)
    - "Mother Hubbard's Kickshaw", 2005 (Box 53)
    - "Mountain Commune", 1980s (Box 53)
    - "Mrs. Mackey's Orchard Cats", 1980s (Box 53)
    - "Mullion", 1990s (Box 53)
    - "Nacelle", undated (Box 53)
    - "Narrow Bridge", circa 2000 (Box 53)
    - "A Narrow Road Through the Far", circa 2000 (Box 54)
    - "Netsuke", undated (Box 54)
    - "New England Graveyard", 1961 September (Box 54)
    - "New Imperial Palace", 1967 (Box 54)
    - "New Leaf Mills", 1990s (Box 54)
    - "New Place", undated (Box 54)
    - "Next Year Vermont", 1970-1985 (Box 54)